# MOHAMMED IMRAN

Software Developer

imohammed12@student.govst.edu

3127099174

CHICAGO, USA

main--ubiquitous-youtiao-f3f1a9.netlify.app/

linkedin.com/in/mohammedimran14

github.com/14IMRAN

Software Developer with experience in all fields of application development from the architect, designing and building Service APIs, User Interfaces, and deploying the application to cloud platforms. I spend a lot of time researching and learning niche technologies. Expert in diverse programming languages, including JavaScript, Java and Python. Directed full development lifecycle, including concept design, feature definitions, and production support Lead global enterprises in making digital transformations through the adoption of modern engineering practices and up-skilling and re-skilling of their existing workforce in the classroom and controlled lab environments Trained software development teams in developing and deploying full-stack JavaScript apps, Node is, Express, React, MongoDB, web performance, product development Led classroom delivery and curriculum development efforts within a team of developers curricular solutions that match needs of Enterprise clients. PORTFOLIO - https://main--ubiquitous-youtiao-f3f1a9.netlify.app/

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

# **FULL STACK DEVELOPER GLASCO TECHNOLOGIES**

05/2021 - 12/2021

SERVICE BASED COMPANY . WORKED FOR CLIENTS FROM CANADA AND

DOR, SCRAPY, MYSQL NODE, AMPLIFY, LIGHTSAIL, HEIDI SQL, MICROSOFT SQL SERVER MANAGEMENT STUDIO

PREDICTIVE MARKETING INTELLIGENCE APPLICATION

- Increased customer base by 24% following a series of dedicated sales campaigns. Tech stack React Js, MongoDb, Node Js,
- Integrated Twilio for managing messaging campaigns and Maligun for sending bulk emails
- Included simple and interactive React charts to visualize the analyzed data
- Department Of Revenue Application
- Leveraged React JS resources for all data access, encapsulating URL's and standardizing data access interfaces. Maintaining Parent and Child component's state by using Redux Js.
- I was responsible for creating RESTFUL Web Services using Node.js & MySql
- Used SQL Server Management Studio and Heidi SQI to manage the backend data that was deployed on Clear Db
- Created CI/CD Pipelines to automate the build, deploy, test and monitoring process

## **DEVELOPER CONSULTANT**

#### ARCALIS.IO

01/2021 - 04/2021

Newcastle UK

- **GENIUS COMMUNICATION APP**
- Developed a communication app in 8 weeks and deployed it to AWS cloud platform
- Tech Stack Reactjs Reduxjs Mongodb Node Js Express Js

## PERSONAL PROJECTS

#### Recommendation System

Given a query user one has to return the n similar users of that query user and give ranking based on similarity in a user-user network model. Built a recommendation system using Spark Hadoop With Amazon product co-purchasing network metadata. 1. Search. The search engine can answer simple and complex queries. Searchable attributes include but are not limited to: Best n sellers of a certain category Number of reviews of a product Queries with enriched operators: > , > =, =, < , < =; e.g.,

# **SKILLS**



## **EDUCATION**

# **JAWAHARLAL NEHRU TECHNOLOGICAL** UNIVERSITY

HYDERBAD, INDIA

09/2020

COMPUTER SCIENCE AND ENGINEERING

- My Major project in engineering was building a Social networking website for developers that is a JavaScript-based project which allows developers to communicate, share ideas, activities, events in the network.
- This system focuses on online communication. Allows the users to promote social responsibilities like development best practices, Startup environment, funding, blogs on building applications that are useful for the viewers.

# **IRONHACK** MADRID. EUROPE

11/2020 - 09/2020

9 week intensive web development boot camp

- Front end technologies learned: HTML | CSS | Javascript ES6 |React
- Version Control: Git | Github
- Back end technologies learned: ExpressJs | NodeJs | MongoDb | Axios